Finding Aid for the Charles S. Mitchell Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Charles S. Mitchell Collection
1876-1963
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0293
2.52 linear_feet
"The love of my life has always been the theatre. I suppose this is inherited both from my father and from my grandmother. I began to go to the. theatre at the age of five, accompanied by my nurse."
Charles S. Mitchell's recollections in 1951 help explain the diversity and chronological span of theatrical and music playbills in the Collection. Since the playbills antedate Charles S. Mitchell's birthdate of 1873, the earlier ones were presumably collected by his father or grandmother. The programs which postdate Mitchell were contributed by Herschel Gower, Department of English, Vanderbilt University. For more reflections by Mitchell, see William Waller's Nashville in the 1890's, pp. 164-74. In this volume Mitchell recollects visiting the roof of Poole's Gallery where E. E. Barnard "with his small telescope showed us the wonders of the skies" (pp. 168-9). Special Collections houses the papers of E. E. Barnard.
In another part of this volume Mrs. George A. Frazer remembers Mitchell's Candies:
Then, there was Mitchell's on Union Street, where the excellence of the candy and the hospitality of the proprieters were known, not only in Nashville, but in other cities. Mr. Mitchell Sr. was a nice-looking gentleman, with gray hair and gray mustache. He was always there, gracious, courtly, never perturbed. His son Charles became the host of the store, and George, the other son, stayed where the candies were made. We met our friends at Mitchell's, bought and enjoyed the candy, and sent it to our friends in Nashville and in other cities.
Special Collections retains a bookmark from Mitchell's Candies.
The materials in the Collection are arranged, whenever the date was known, in chronological order by year and in alphabetical order. Some abbreviated notation gives the city for places other than those coded.
Some notable materials in the Collection are programs from vocal and instrumental concerts and performances at Theatre Vendome as well as Little Theatre productions in Nashville. Of particular interest to the Fugitive/Agrarian Collection are two programs from two plays by Andrew Lytle: The Lost Sheep is in Box 2, 1932; The Gold Tooth, a Calumet Players' Presentation (Vanderbilt Theatrical Group), is in Box 4, undated. Other interesting productions include performances starring Maude Adams, Sarah Bernhardt, Paul Robeson in Othello (1944). Programs include Lillian Hellman's The Searching Wind (1944), Song of Norway (1945) choreography by George Balanchine, the first American engagement of Old Vic, and various items on Shakespearean productions. The Charles S. Mitchell Collection also contains some miscellaneous English productions.
Box 1 includes correspondence and playbills from 1866-1921
Box 2 includes correspondence and playbills from 1922-1934
Box 3 includes correspondence and playbills from 1936-1947
Box 4 includes includes correspondence and playbills from 1948-1952; playbills from 1952-1963 donated by Mitchell's friend Herschel Gower, faculty member of the Vanderbilt English Department; and programs with no date.
Box 5 includes newspaper clippings, librettos, pamphlets, playbills, miscellaneous. Some of the playbills in Box 5 were also donated by Herschel Gower. Theatre Vendome programs (ca. 1913-1916), which were printed on newsprint paper and thus are extremely fragile, are included in this Box.
Box 6 includes photographs of theatrical performers.
General Contents:
Playbills - Programs - 1876-1963 ca. 450 items - (45 N.D.)
Librettos - 6 items
Miscellaneous pamphlets - 20 items
Photographs of actors, actresses and musicians
Newspaper clippings
Correspondence, incoming:
Cheatham, Frances B. (no date) - 1 letter
Milne, A. C. - 1929, July 24 - 1 letter
Robinson, Francis - 1949, Sept. 24 - 1 letter
"Buddy" - no date - 1 letter
No signature - no date
4 letters - 1 card
The Old Vic Company, 1914-1963 - Issued to commemorate the final performance saturday - 15th June, 1963
The Old Vic Company, 1914-1963 is located with the English Dept.'s materials
- Correspondence - Incoming
  - Cheatham, Frances B, n.d., 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Milne, A. C, July 24, 1929, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - Robinson, Francis, September 24, 1949, 1 letter (Box 1)
  - "Buddy,", n.d., 1 letter (Box 1)
  - No signature, n.d., 4 letters, 1 card (Box 1)
- Playbills and Programs
  - Belphegor the Mountebank stars Chas. Dillion - Cherry Street Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Bohemian Girl! By M. W. Balfe and farce Dobson Bamboozled! - Holman Opera Troupe, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Hanlon Brothers! (gymnasts) and Prof. Sylvester! and Mrs. W. Tanner! - Nashville (Box 1)
  - Ingomar the Barbarian stars Jean Hosmer and farce Rough Diamond! - Nashville (Box 1)
  - La Tour de Nesle! or The Chamber of Death and burletta Anthony and Cleopatra - Cherry Street Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Lucretia Borgia! or The Poisoner! stars Jean Hosmer and drama Jack Sheppard: the House-Breaker - Cherry Street Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Mazeppa! or, The Young King of Tartary adapted from Lord Byron's drama stars Adah Issacs Menken includes Nashville Tennesean clipping on Menken (July 28, 1948) - Nashville (Box 1)
  - Lady of Lyons or Love and Pride stars Charlotte Thompson and The Merry Cobbler - Adelphi Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Little Treasure stars Charlotte Thompson and Day After the Wedding - Adelphi Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - The Streets of New York - Adelphi Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Grand Vocal Concert, Second Baptist on Tuesday, September 29, 1868 - Cherry Street, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Bianca the Italian Wife stars Jean Hosmer and Fazio! or The Italian Wife's Revenge by Reverend Henry Hart Milmore and The Toodles! - New Nashville Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Elizabeth Queen of England stas Mrs. F. W. Lander - New Nashville Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Grand Concert Benefit of West Nashville M. E. Church, South on Friday, October 29, 1869 - Nashville (Box 1)
  - Grand Medley Concert at Masonic Hall on December 16, 17, 1869 - Nashville (Box 1)
  - Grand Sunday School Concert at Masonic Hall on Monday, July 19, 1869 - Nashville (Box 1)
  - Grand Vocal and Instrumental Concert at Masonic Hall on Friday, June 18, 1869 - Nashville (Box 1)
  - School for Scandal stars Mrs. F. W. Lander - New Nashville Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Grand Concert for the Benefit of the Church of the Advent at Masonic Hall on Tuesday, November 1, 1970 - Nashville (Box 1)
  - Mary Stuart, Schiller's Historical Play, stars Janauschek, 1873 - Masonic Hall, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Everybody's Friend! stars John E. Owens, 1874 and Solon Shingle - Opera House, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Happy Man! (Irish oriental farce) stars J. Holmes Grover and Handy Andy! - Nashville (Box 1)
  - The Heir-at-Law! (grand English comedy) stars John E. Owens, 1874 and 40 Winks! - Opera House, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Peak Family Bell Ringers! (Box 1)
  - Tosso (violinist), Emily Young (vocalist), McCann (ventriloquist) and Melzell1 s French Troupe of Fantoccini unidentifiable music program (Box 1)
  - Edmund Kean by Alex. Dumas stars Ernesto Rossi, 1882 and a scene from King Lear - Chestnut Street Opera House, P (Box 1)
  - A Night Off or A Page from Balzac by Augustin Daly, 1885 and Epilogue in Verse by Edgar Fawcett - Daly's Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Nancy and Company by Augustin Daly, 1886 - Daly's Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Magda by H. Sudermann, English argument by E. Beall Ginty, 1896 The Bernhardt edition (Box 1)
  - Pique! - Daly's Fifth Avenue Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Irish-American Centennial Association of Tennessee Booklet, September 21, 1897 (Box 1)
  - A Contented Woman, 1898 - New Masonic Theatre, Nashville (Box 1)
  - The Highwayman - Theatre Vendome, Nashville (Box 1)
  - The Little Minister by J. M. Barrie stars Maude Adams - Hollis Street Theatre Boston (Box 1)
  - The Burgomaster, 50th performance theatre souvenir - Dearborn Thatre (Box 1)
  - Beaucaire (2) a comedy by Booth Tarkington and Evelyn G. Sutherland, stars Richard Mansfield - Colonial Theatre, Boston (Box 1)
  - Florodora, an English musical comedy, book by Owen Hall and music by Leslie Stuart - The New York Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Hoity Toity, a Giddy Little Skit on Things Dramatic and Otherwise, lyrics by Edgar Smith and music by John Stromberg - Webster and Fields Music Hall, New York City (Box 1)
  - If I Were King by Justin H. McCarthy stars E. H. Sothern - Garden Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - L'Aiglon by Edmond Rostand, adapted into English by Louis N. Parker, a pictorial souvenir - R. H. Russell Publisher, New York City (Box 1)
  - Miranda of the Balcony by Anne C. Flexner stars Mrs. Fiske - Manhattan Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Mrs. Dane's Defence by Henry Arthur Jones - Hollis Street Theatre, Boston (Box 1)
  - Sky Farm, a simple story of the Berkshire Hills, by Edward E. Kidder - Boston Museum, Boston (Box 1)
  - Otis Skinner Presenting George H. Boker's Tragedy Francesca Da Rimini (Book) (Box 1)
  - Grand Opera House Program: week of May 5, 1902 - Nashville, The Merchant May 5 The First Anniversary May 7 The Camp Scene from Virginius The Death Shot One Touch of Nature May 9 Comedy and Tragedy by W. S. Gilbert The Balcony Scene from Romeo and Juliet (Box 1)
  - The Marble Heart by Charles Selbey - Grand Opera House, Nashville (Box 1)
  - The Merchant of Venice by William Shakespeare - Grand Opera House, Nashville (Box 1)
  - The Darling of the Gods stars Blanche Bates David's Belasco's Exposition Production (Box 1)
  - As Ye Sow, a drama founded on life and incidents on Cape Cod, by Rev. John M. Snyder - Majestic Theatre, Boston (Box 1)
  - Camille, La Dame aux Camelias, by Alexandre Dumas The Sarah Bernhardt edition (Box 1)
  - Camille - Ryman Auditorium, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Man and Superman by Bernard Shaw - Hudson Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Music Master by Charles Klein stars David Warfield - Bijou Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Oliver Twist by Charles Dickens - Proctor's Fifth Avenue Theatre New York City (Box 1)
  - Zaza stars Mrs. Leslie Carter - Belasco Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Zira by J. Hartley Manners and Henry Mille stars Margaret Anglin - Princess Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - A Parisian Romance by Octave Feuillet - Colonial Theatre, Boston (Box 1)
  - Divorcons by Victorien Sardou, adapted from the French by Margaret Mayo, stars Grace George - Hollis Street, Boston (Box 1)
  - The Great Divide by William Vaughn Moody stars Margaret Anglin and Henry Miller - Daly's Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Master Builder by Henrik Ibsen - Bijou Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Melting Pot by Israel Zangwill stars Mr. Whiteside - Chicago Opera House Chicago (Box 1)
  - Anna Lundberg Concert on September 12, 1909 - Orchestra Hall, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Climax by Edward Locke - Weber's Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Easiest Way by Eugene Walter stars Frances Starr - Belasco's Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Man from Home by Booth Tarkington and Harry Leon Wilson stars Mr. William Hodge - Astor Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Messiah by Handel - Apollo Musical Club, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Passing of the Third Floor Back by Jerome K. Jerome - Maxine Elliott's Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - What Every Woman Knows by J. M. Barrie stars Maude Adams - Grand Opera House, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Herod by Stephen Phillips stars William Faversham - Garrick Theatre (Box 1)
  - La Samaritaine by M-. Edmond Rostand stars Sarah Bernhardt and Company - The Studebaker, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Madame X by Alexandre Bisson as presented by by Sarah Bernhardt (argument of the play) (Box 1)
  - Mr. Mantell and his Company in a Repertoire of Shakespearean and Other Classical Plays for the week of November 21, 1910 - Lyric Theatre, Chicago, King Lear Louis XI Romeo and Juliet Macbeth The Merchant of Venice Richard III (Box 1)
  - Ragged Robin- stars Chauncey Olcott - McVicker's Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Ruth by Georg Schumann - Apollo Musical Club, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Concert by Herman Bahr - Belasco Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Disraeli by Louis N. Parker - Wallack's, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Great Name by James Clarence Harvey - Thirty-ninth Street Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Return of Peter Grimm by David Belasco - Belasco Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Shakespeare - Lyric Theatre, Chicago, The Taming of the Shrew The Merchant of Venice Hamlet Romeo and Juliet (Box 1)
  - Thais (in French) Lyric Romance by Jules Massenet - Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Thief adapted into English by Haddon Chambers - Daily's Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Bunty Pulls the Strings, A Scottish Comedy, by Graham Moffat - William Collier's Comedy Theatre NY New York City (Box 1)
  - Chantecler by Edmond Rostand - Illinois Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Romance by Edward Sheldon - The Princess Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Wall Street Girl, book by Margaret Maho and Egar Selwyn and music by Karl Hoschna, stars Will Rogers - Theatre Vendome, Nashville (Box 1)
  - Caesar and Cleopatra by George Bernard Shaw - Blackstone Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - If I Were King by Justin Huntley McCarthy stars E. H. Sothern - Garrick Theatre, Chicago, Our American Cousin by Tom Taylor stars E. H. Sothern Hamlet by William Shakespeare stars E. H. Sothern Charlemagne by Justin Huntley McCarthy stars E. H. Sothern (Box 1)
  - Androcles and the Lion by George Bernard Shaw - Powers' Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Man Who Married a Dumb Wife by Anatole France - Powers' Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Anna Pavlowa and Her Ballet Russe April 2, 1915 - Auditorium Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Song Recital by John McCormack Benefit Performance for Italian Red Cross and Invalid Pensioners - Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera Chicago (Box 1)
  - Common Clay by Cleves Kinkead - Olympic Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Hamlet (Farewell of Forbes-Robertson to the the American Stage on April 24, 25, 26, 1916, Shakespeare Tercentenary) at Harvard - Cambridge, Massachusetts (Box 1)
  - His Majesty Bunker Bean by Lee Wilson Dodd - Cort Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Little Minister by J. M. Barrie stars Maude Adams - Blackstone Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Two Virtues by Alfred Sutro - Blackstone Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Lilac-Time by Jane Cowl and Jane Murfin - George M. Cohan Grand Opera House Chicago (Box 1)
  - Aida (in Italian) by Giuseppe Verdi - Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Acquittal by Rita Weiman - George M. Cohan Grand Opera House Chicago (Box 1)
  - Déclassée by Zoe Akins stars Ethel Barrymore - Empire Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - First Annual Testimonial Performance in the Interest of the Actors' Fidelity League Sunday, October 12, 1919 - Century Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Gold Diggers by Avery Hopwood - Lyceum Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Happiness by J. Hartley Manners - Blackstone Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Jacques Duvall (adapted) by George S. Kaufman - Blackstone Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Jest (adapted from the Italian of Sem Benelli's La Cena delle Beffe) stars Johri and Lionel Barrymore settings by Robert Edmund Jones - Plymouth Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - Lightin' by Winchell Smith and Frank Bacon - Gaiety Theatre, New York City (Box 1)
  - The Masquerader by John Hunter Booth - Studebaker Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - Tillie by Helen Martin and Frank Howe, Jr. - Blackstone Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Barber of Seville (in Italian) by Rossini - Auditorium Theatre, Chicago Grand Opera Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Woman of Bronze by Paul Kester - Princess Theatre, Chicago (Box 1)
  - The Circle by W. Somerset Maugham - Selwyn Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - Sir Harry Lauder - Shubert Great Northern, Chicago (Box 2)
  - Nice People by Rachel Crothers - Cort Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - The Silver Fox by Cosmo Hamilton - La Salle Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - La Traviata by Verdi - Chicago Civic Opera, Chicago (Box 2)
  - The School for Scandal by Richard Sheridan - Lyceum Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - So This is London by Arthur Goodrich - George M. Cohan's Opera House New York City (Box 2)
  - Windows (2) by John Galsworthy - Garrick Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Wappin' Wharf, a frightful comedy of pirates, by Charles S. Brooks - Little Theatre of Birmingham, Alabama (Box 2)
  - Charlot's Revue - Selwyn Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Green Rat by Michael Arlen - Selwyn Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Hamlet with Walter Hampden and Ethel Barrymore - Hampden's, New York City (Box 2)
  - Is Zat So? by James Gleason and Richard Taber - Chanin's Forty-sixth Street Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Rose-Marie by Otto Harbach and Oscar Hammerstein - Imperial Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Second Mrs. Tanqueray by Sir Arthur Wing Pinero - Blackstone Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - The Show-off, a transcript of life, by George Kelly - New Park Theatre, Boston (Box 2)
  - Stolen Fruit by Dario Niccodemi - Eltinge Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - They Knew What They Wanted by Sidney Howard - Ktaw Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Vortex by Noel Coward - Henry Miller's Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Black Velvet by Willard Robertson - Playhouse Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - The Master Builder by Henrik Ibsen - Shubert Princess Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - The Miracle by Maz Reinhardt - Shubert Auditorium Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - Q by Stephen Leacock and Basil MacDonald Hastings - Player's Playhouse of Ypsilanti (Box 2)
  - The School for Scandal by Richard Sheridan - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Star Sapphire by Robert Housum - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Vanishing Princess by John Golden - Player's Playhouse of Ypsilanti (Box 2)
  - What Every Woman Knows by J. M. Barrie - Four Cohans Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Yellow Triangle by George Sutton, Jr. - Player's Playhouse of Ypsilanti New York City (Box 2)
  - Drama Calender for February 22, 1926 - New York City (Box 2)
  - Butterfly Hearts by Marion H. Mimms - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Host by Ferenc Molnar - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Mrs. Bumpstead-Leigh by Harry James Smith - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - White Elephants by Kenyon Nicholson - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Bachelor Father by Edward Childs Carpenter - Hollis Street Theatre, Boston (Box 2)
  - The Butter and Egg Man by George Kaufmann and Marc Connelly - Little Theatre Guild, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Constant Wife by W. Somerset Maugham - Sam H. Harris Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - Coquette by George Abbot and Ann Preston Bridgers stars Helen Hayes - Shubert-Wilbur Theatre, Boston (Box 2)
  - The Civic Repertory Theatre Program for the weeks of October 8 and 15 - Civic Repertory Theatre, New York City, The Cradle Song by Gregorio and Maria M. Sierra Hedda Gabler by Henrik Ibsen (rev. trans.) by Julie Le Gallienne and Paul Leyssac La Locandiera by Carlo Goldoni (trans. and adapted) by Helen Lohmann L'Invitation Au Voyage by Jean-Jacques Bernard (trans.) by Ernest Boyd The Would-Be Gentleman by Moliere (adapted) by F. Anstey (Box 2)
  - Exceeding Small by Caroline Francke - The Comedy Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Goin' Home by Ransom Rideout - Theatre Masque, New York City (Box 2)
  - Machinal by Sophie Treadwell - The Plymouth Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Red Robe by Stanley Weyman - Sam S. Shubert Theatre, Boston (Box 2)
  - S. S. Incorporated by Verne Jay and Frances Jewett - Repertory Theatre of Boston, Boston (Box 2)
  - Strange Interlude by Eugene O'Neil - The Golden Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Civic Repertory Theatre Schedule of Plays for the weeks of October 22-November 12 - Civic Repertory Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - It's a Wise Child by Laurence Johnson - Belasco Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Strictly Dishonorable by Preston Sturges - Avon Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Cradle Song by G. and Maria Martinez Sierra - Nashville Little Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Her Husband's Wife by A. E. Thomas - Nashville Little Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Royal Family by Edna Ferber and George Kaufman - Nashville Little Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Sea Gull by Anton Tcheckov - Nashville Little Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Barretta of Wimpole Street by R. Besier - Empire Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Broadway by George Abbot and Phillip Dunning - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Dancing Mothers by Edwin Goulding and Edgar Selwyn - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - A Doll's House by Henrik Ibsen - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Fourth Wall by A. A. Milne - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Front Page by Ben Hecht and C.. MacArthur - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Grand Hotel by Vicki Baum - National Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Guardsman by Ferene Molnar - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Mrs. Moonlight by Benn W. Levy - Little Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - A Noble Outcast by John Frazer - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Petticoat Influence by Neil Grant - Lyceum Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Private Lives by Noel Coward - Times Square Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Queen's Husband by Robert Emmet Sherwood - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Three's A Company by Howard Dietz - Selwyn Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Vinegar Tree by Paul Osborn - Playhouse Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Boor by Anton Tchekov - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Cynara by Philip Merivale - Sam S. Shubert Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Diplomacy by Victorien Sardou - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Ghosts by Henrik Ibsen - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Ladies of the Jury by Fred Ballard - Hillsboro Tneatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Lost Sheep by Andrew Nelson Lytle - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - The Valiant by Holworthy Hall and Robert Middlemass - Hillsboro Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Alien Corn by Sidney Howard - Harris Theatre, Chicago (Box 2)
  - Alice Sit-by-the-Fire by Sir James Barrie - Nashville Experimental Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Ah, Wilderness! by Eugene O'Neil with George M. Cohan - Plymouth Theatre, Boston (Box 2)
  - Between Two Worlds by Elmer Rice - Belasco Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Dodsworth by Sinclair Lewis - Sam S. Shubert Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Distaff Side by John Van Druten - The Booth Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Judgment Day by Elmer Rice - Fulton Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Merrily We Roll Along by George S. Kaufman and Moss Hart - The Music Box, New York City (Box 2)
  - The Mikado by W. S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan - Martin Beck Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Once in a Lifetime by George Kaufman and Moss - Nashville Experimental Theatre, Nashville (Box 2)
  - Personal Appearance by Lawrence Riley - Henry Miller's Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - A Sleeping Clergyman by James Bridie - Guild Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Stevedore by Paul Peters and George Sklar - Civic Repertory Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Tobacco Road by Jack Kirkland (based on a novel by Erskine Caldwell) - Forrest Theatre, New York City (Box 2)
  - Tristan and Isolde by Richard Wagner - Chicago Grand Opera, Chicago (Box 2)
  - Boy Meets Girl by Bella and Samuel Spewack - Cort Theatre, New York City (Box 3)
  - Bury the Dead by Irwin Shaw preceded by Prelude (Actors' Repertory Company) - Ethel Barrymore Theatre, New York City (Box 3)